<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musings on OSINTEL Project</title>
    <link>https://osintelproject.org/musings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Musings on OSINTEL Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osintelproject.org/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to OSINTELProject and Happy New Year</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/musings/new-year-and-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/musings/new-year-and-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hello and Happy New Year
I thought it might be nice to welcome any visitors that somehow come across this site. I have not been trying to really promote this site for any wide readership but if you do happen to find this site that&amp;rsquo;s great. Feel free to spread the word if so desired.
Daily Rundown Since we are now in 2022 I thought it made sense to come up with a new goal for the 1 year anniversary of OSINTELProject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sourcing Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/musings/sourcing-philosphy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/musings/sourcing-philosphy/</guid>
      <description>Philosophy and Disclaimer One of the intentions of this site is to merge sources from academia, Think Tanks, and journalists. In my estimation this is where OSINT is lacking. Typically I think of as OSINT as more for the cybersecurity nerd worried about exploitations of zero days and cyber ops. Much of that is done via Twitter analytics by looking at various topics and motioring their web traffic. That&amp;rsquo;s all well and good if you like that stuff but I believe this provides a skewed understanding of a topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When in Doubt use AI/ML</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/musings/when-in-doubt-use-ai-and-ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/musings/when-in-doubt-use-ai-and-ml/</guid>
      <description>Anomalous Health Incidents (AHI), also known as Havana Syndrome.
The US Intel Community has been baffled by the source of AHIs and a leaked report of the reported source of these ‘attacks’ has not happened. I.e., there is still conflicting evidence on what is causing this and if a human entity is responsible.
One interesting theory is crickets causing the issue. Buzzfeed received a declassified State Department Report by the JASON board of scientists in November 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Montogmery McFate up to these days?</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/musings/what-is-montogmery-mcfate-up-to-these-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/musings/what-is-montogmery-mcfate-up-to-these-days/</guid>
      <description>Background: Montgomery McFate is an anthropologist whose dissertation was on the case study of the British counterinsurgency of Northern Ireland (1969-1982). McFate then went on to RAND and the US Navy’s Office of Naval Research (ONR). This is all on her website. She was the co-creator of the Human Terrain System ,an outside fix of the United States military lack of cultural knowledge during the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Drone Strikes</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/musings/reflection-on-drone-strikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/musings/reflection-on-drone-strikes/</guid>
      <description>Most people go about their lives unaware of this policy. It&amp;rsquo;s out of sight, out of mind. There is also not much else to do besides monitoring if you are a civilian. Most people who do focus on the issue, decry drone strikes without actual information and simply see it as an extrajudicial killing or assassination and go about their lives. There is a very specific type of outlet which actually monitors these strikes, and much of it is done on Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rblogdown Setup</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/musings/rblogdown-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/musings/rblogdown-setup/</guid>
      <description>Alright I finally was able to setup Rblogdown with something resembling a type that I wanted. The biggest problem I had was the inability to figure out a decent workflow of things.
RStudioHugoNetlifyThat&amp;rsquo;s the main way to get these things to all talk together. Here&amp;rsquo;s a helpful video tutorial of the setup. My biggest issue I had was with Hugo. They have a bunch of different themes but I didn&amp;rsquo;t like very many of them and I have no html, css, javascript or bootstrap experience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
