<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finished Books on OSINTEL Project</title>
    <link>https://osintelproject.org/tags/finished-books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finished Books on OSINTEL Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osintelproject.org/tags/finished-books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rise and Kill first: The Secret History of Israel&#39;s Targeted Assassinations</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/rise-and-kill-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/rise-and-kill-first/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts Well this book took forever to finish. At 631 pages it took some time to read and slog through. My understanding of Israel is limited so this was more of a starting text for shedding light on how it views assassinations. Israel also plays a factor in current JCPOA discussions which is why I was also interested in it.
Also this book continues to make headlines in thinktank and academic circles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never mind, we&#39;ll do it ourselves </title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/well-do-it-ourselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/well-do-it-ourselves/</guid>
      <description>States they killed Abu Muhammad al-Masri in November of 2001. Pg 262-70.
They really mean the military commander Abu Hafs al-Masri. (Atef)
“ [&amp;hellip;] On the night of November 15, 2001 coalition missiles hit the home of al-Qa&amp;rsquo;ida’s military chief, Abu Hafs al-Masri, crumpling it into a pile of stones at the bottom of a deep crater. While most al-Qa&amp;rsquo;ida commanders had evacuated, Abu Hafs had been unable to do so because of a slipped disk in his back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little America</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/little-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/little-america/</guid>
      <description>Alright so this a new year and I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to become much more accountable towards my daily writing endeavors.
I just finished Rajiv Chandrasekaran&amp;rsquo;s book Little America. I&amp;rsquo;ve previously read his Life in the Emerald City about his reporting in Iraq. There are few reporters in my opinion that can do what he can and the importance of both of these two books will stand the test of time to later be used by historians in the ensuing years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
