<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on OSINTEL Project</title>
    <link>https://osintelproject.org/tags/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on OSINTEL Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osintelproject.org/tags/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sourcing Philosophy</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/musings/sourcing-philosphy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/musings/sourcing-philosphy/</guid>
      <description>Philosophy and Disclaimer One of the intentions of this site is to merge sources from academia, Think Tanks, and journalists. In my estimation this is where OSINT is lacking. Typically I think of as OSINT as more for the cybersecurity nerd worried about exploitations of zero days and cyber ops. Much of that is done via Twitter analytics by looking at various topics and motioring their web traffic. That&amp;rsquo;s all well and good if you like that stuff but I believe this provides a skewed understanding of a topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Discussions Continued</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-10/</guid>
      <description>In the last post about these diplomatic talks, briefly mentioned was the Natanz blackout. The immediate sources claimed this was caused by a possible cyberattack by Israel.
Since then the nature of the attack is much clearer and it was in fact an explosion on 10 April 2021. This explosion targeted the internal power supply of the enrichment facility and the Nytimes quoted US intelligence sources, which claimed that this explosion set back enrichment efforts 9 months and had Israeli involvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iran Cyberattack</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-9/</guid>
      <description>Well that was quick.
Just after updating the current diplomatic &amp;ldquo;shuttle diplomacy&amp;rdquo; (dumb term in my opinion. Also indirect talks among others) going on in Vienna, this Sunday an electric blackout occurred at Natanz, Iran. Iran labeled this a terrorist attack and journalists are calling this a cyberattack.
Just yesterday Iran announced their use of 164 IR-6 centrifuges for uranium enrichment.
AP&amp;rsquo;s version here, Guardian here, and AFP here and here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Grandstanding</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-8/</guid>
      <description>For the past year or so I’ve been paying attention to this whole fiasco of nuclear grandstanding between the United States and Iran.
Basic preliminary instances that brought us to things today.
2018
•	8 MAY – United States withdraws from US led JCPOA nuclear agreement
•	NOVEMBER – Start of Maximum Pressure Campaign
2019
•	8 MAY – Iran officially announced abandoning some JCPOA elements.
•	20 JUNE – US drone shot down over Iranian airspace</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to View a Source</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-7/</guid>
      <description>Rules of Thumb: Every source is suspect. No source will ever be completely factually correct no matter who its author. A great deal of skepticism is needed when analyzing and evaluating new information.
What is the publishing history of the author of the source?
What is the motive to release or publish this source?
What platform is this source on?
Are the sources named or unnamed? What does the bibliography look like?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
