<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iran on OSINTEL Project</title>
    <link>https://osintelproject.org/tags/iran/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iran on OSINTEL Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osintelproject.org/tags/iran/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JCPOA Talks Resume</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-15/</guid>
      <description>JCPOA Stuff Negotiations resumed between Iran and the P5+1 on 29 November in Vienna, but with the US in a hotel across the street and everyone else at the Palais Coburg hotel. (Other Coordinates: OpenStreetMap &amp;amp; HERE WeGo)
An article by Vali Nasr
https://english.almayadeen.net/news/politics/al-mayadeen:-jcpoa-negotiations-in-vienna-to-resume-next-wee
Yemen  https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/saudi-coalition-targets-hothis-sites-yemens-sanaa-state-tv-2021-11-30/ Houthi-Salafi Coexistence Agreements: Motives and Future Prospects https://sanaacenter.org/publications/analysis/15839 (Late Add) Carneigie ThinkTank Roundtable about GCC post Hydrocarborns. Some discussion on Yemen at here.  Turkey&amp;rsquo;s Inflation Nonsense Erdoğan has sacked 3 central bank managers in the past 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Status on US Side</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-14/</guid>
      <description>Negotiations in Vienna are set to resume on 29 November between Iran and Europe. There has been very little movement or progress with renegotiating the JCPOA. General arguments for the long delay cite Iranian elections at the end of June and the US withdrawal from Afghanistan in August but these are half truths at best for explaining this delay.
A Business Insider article by Chatham House’s Sanam Vakil (Senior Research Fellow of MENA) provides a succinct summary of the past few months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Hits</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-12/</guid>
      <description>Interesting Iranian Op on US Soil
So a few days ago the US DOJ just released an indictment of 4 Iranian individuals who conspired to kidnap or coerce Masih Alinejad an American-Iranian human rights activist to come back to Iran. The DOJ press release can be found here and the Masih’s account of the issue via the UAE news site The National is here. First case to my knowledge of something like this happening on US soil against a US citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update for US/Iranian Diplomacy</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-11/</guid>
      <description>Hmm, what&amp;rsquo;s been going on over the past month or so?
Well, for the discussions not much has progressed over a continued belief of cautious optimism. There have been five rounds of discussions and this week there is a break before talks resume again.
Overall stance of both parties has not changed. US- Iran remove nuclear stockpile before sanctions lifted. Iran- US remove sanctions and then rejoin JCPOA.
There are a few notable events leading to this state of affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Discussions Continued</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-10/</guid>
      <description>In the last post about these diplomatic talks, briefly mentioned was the Natanz blackout. The immediate sources claimed this was caused by a possible cyberattack by Israel.
Since then the nature of the attack is much clearer and it was in fact an explosion on 10 April 2021. This explosion targeted the internal power supply of the enrichment facility and the Nytimes quoted US intelligence sources, which claimed that this explosion set back enrichment efforts 9 months and had Israeli involvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iran Cyberattack</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-9/</guid>
      <description>Well that was quick.
Just after updating the current diplomatic &amp;ldquo;shuttle diplomacy&amp;rdquo; (dumb term in my opinion. Also indirect talks among others) going on in Vienna, this Sunday an electric blackout occurred at Natanz, Iran. Iran labeled this a terrorist attack and journalists are calling this a cyberattack.
Just yesterday Iran announced their use of 164 IR-6 centrifuges for uranium enrichment.
AP&amp;rsquo;s version here, Guardian here, and AFP here and here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Grandstanding</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-8/</guid>
      <description>For the past year or so I’ve been paying attention to this whole fiasco of nuclear grandstanding between the United States and Iran.
Basic preliminary instances that brought us to things today.
2018
•	8 MAY – United States withdraws from US led JCPOA nuclear agreement
•	NOVEMBER – Start of Maximum Pressure Campaign
2019
•	8 MAY – Iran officially announced abandoning some JCPOA elements.
•	20 JUNE – US drone shot down over Iranian airspace</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
