<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>World News on OSINTEL Project</title>
    <link>https://osintelproject.org/tags/world-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in World News on OSINTEL Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osintelproject.org/tags/world-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Where to go from here?</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-17/</guid>
      <description>JCPOA News **So unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;m a bit out of touch with all of the nuance going on with these negotiations over the past two weeks. Some things I have read for following recent events I&amp;rsquo;ve relegated to tweeting out and others I have not been able to set aside the proper amount of time to provide any decent sort of synopsis of how things stand. See here for a brief summary of the past couple weeks from an Iranian source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Pandering</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-16/</guid>
      <description>JCPOA 1. Not a great week by all accounts  Global media coverage of the first week has not been altogether positive. Diplomats reconvened yesterday 11/12/2021 for a resumption of talks, largely at the behest of China and Russia.
2. More US military and Israeli aggressive proclamations Yemen Follow Up The Sana&amp;rsquo;a Center has updated its Yemen Review publication with an update on the current Mar&amp;rsquo;ib offensive.1 From the looks of things the Saudi coalition has continued to be pushed back despite an earlier claim of killing aprox 200 enemy fighters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JCPOA Talks Resume</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-15/</guid>
      <description>JCPOA Stuff Negotiations resumed between Iran and the P5+1 on 29 November in Vienna, but with the US in a hotel across the street and everyone else at the Palais Coburg hotel. (Other Coordinates: OpenStreetMap &amp;amp; HERE WeGo)
An article by Vali Nasr
https://english.almayadeen.net/news/politics/al-mayadeen:-jcpoa-negotiations-in-vienna-to-resume-next-wee
Yemen  https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/saudi-coalition-targets-hothis-sites-yemens-sanaa-state-tv-2021-11-30/ Houthi-Salafi Coexistence Agreements: Motives and Future Prospects https://sanaacenter.org/publications/analysis/15839 (Late Add) Carneigie ThinkTank Roundtable about GCC post Hydrocarborns. Some specific discussion about Yemen below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Status on US Side</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-14/</guid>
      <description>Negotiations in Vienna are set to resume on 29 November between Iran and Europe. There has been very little movement or progress with renegotiating the JCPOA. General arguments for the long delay cite Iranian elections at the end of June and the US withdrawal from Afghanistan in August but these are half truths at best for explaining this delay.
A Business Insider article by Chatham House’s Sanam Vakil (Senior Research Fellow of MENA) provides a succinct summary of the past few months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Hits</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/daily-rundown/blog-12/</guid>
      <description>Interesting Iranian Op on US Soil
So a few days ago the US DOJ just released an indictment of 4 Iranian individuals who conspired to kidnap or coerce Masih Alinejad an American-Iranian human rights activist to come back to Iran. The DOJ press release can be found here and the Masih’s account of the issue via the UAE news site The National is here. First case to my knowledge of something like this happening on US soil against a US citizen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
