<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Category 66 on OSINTEL Project</title>
    <link>https://osintelproject.org/categories/category-66/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Category 66 on OSINTEL Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://osintelproject.org/categories/category-66/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sinews of War and Trade: Shipping and Capitalism in the Arabian Peninsula</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/sinews-of-war-and-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/sinews-of-war-and-trade/</guid>
      <description>Laleh Khalili is a Professor of INternational Politics at Queen Mary University of London and recently (2020) wrote this book. Familiar with her book Time in the Shadows: Confinement in Counterinsurgencies.
Blurb This book provides a helpful introduction to the reshapping of global sea trade after decolonisation. I found this book interesting mainly due to my own ignorace of the global maritime industry and how this relates to the importance of the Gulf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rise and Kill first: The Secret History of Israel&#39;s Targeted Assassinations</title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/rise-and-kill-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/rise-and-kill-first/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts Well this book took forever to finish. At 631 pages it took some time to read and slog through. My understanding of Israel is limited so this was more of a starting text for shedding light on how it views assassinations. Israel also plays a factor in current JCPOA discussions which is why I was also interested in it.
Also this book continues to make headlines in thinktank and academic circles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never mind, we&#39;ll do it ourselves </title>
      <link>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/well-do-it-ourselves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://osintelproject.org/book-reviews/well-do-it-ourselves/</guid>
      <description>States they killed Abu Muhammad al-Masri in November of 2001. Pg 262-70.
They really mean the military commander Abu Hafs al-Masri. (Atef)
“ [&amp;hellip;] On the night of November 15, 2001 coalition missiles hit the home of al-Qa&amp;rsquo;ida’s military chief, Abu Hafs al-Masri, crumpling it into a pile of stones at the bottom of a deep crater. While most al-Qa&amp;rsquo;ida commanders had evacuated, Abu Hafs had been unable to do so because of a slipped disk in his back.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
